Hello, my friends, and welcome to exercise number 26.
It's about three character.
So explain the functionality of the following function function two and it took in the parameter and
end, so it checks if an equal equal to zero it were returned otherwise a function to well being being
being called again and over to and then it will print.
OK.
This is in language.
See OK.
So both the video and think about it.
Now, if function f of two, a function to as taking an equal to 21.
So I am going to calculate F of 20.
One are passing f of 21 here.
OK.
Now, if unequal, equal to zero return and is not equal to see it is being executed like this way function
equal and over two, we divide.
We call it again, we call it again, the function.
But here we are, going to divide and over do so.
21 divided by two.
The 21 divided by two is ten point five, but sits and since and is an integer.
We took that only that integer part.
So it is not ten point five.
It is.
And so then it stops here and call F of 10 now.
It calls F of 10 again, if an equal equal to zero, no function.
Two and over to it will call the function again F of an offer to choose five.
OK.
And equal equal to zero.
No, it will return.
Then it will call the function and over two.
So f of five, it will call f of 2.5, but two point five you cannot write 2.5 because an equal to enter
is an integer.
So it is two.
We took on the integer part f of two.
Half of, too, it will go and check and equal equal to zero.
No, again, go and execute and over.
Do you see guys that we didn't execute the print here because we are just using that expression and
we are following that character.
So f of doom, it is calling f of one because and over two to over one sorry, two over two as one again
as of one going up and equal equal to zero.
Now it would go down and f calling f of n over two.
So one over two is equal to 0.5, but since and is equal or as an integer.
So we took that integer part and we removed the decimal part.
So it is f off.
See you now going up and equal equal to zero.
Yes.
So it is going to be returning.
OK.
So it will return.
So what happens when it returns, it returns.
So the function f of zero is returning.
So this will not return anything.
It just skip it.
So F1 now continues, it reaches here and call of zero and f of zero is telling her, No, I go and
continue that process.
So it will prevent AF that the percentage that percentage of and modulo to so and modulo two and in
this case is equal to one and modulo two is equal to one because one modulo two is equal to one.
OK.
The remainder is equal to one.
So this is one going up, going up to f of two.
We said that recursion is going back.
So F of two, it reaches F of two and call f of one.
And after finishing here and getting the answer of one, it will continue and the f in the calls.
So think about the council is here.
We have got one as the first element because f of zero returning so we can return it, telling f of
hey f of one contenir your code so it will continue with Brent F and it will print the M Model two,
which is one again going up to f off to f of two as telling or F1 is telling F2 Hey f off to continue
that program, it will continue and print f.
So in this case, and modular two end model two here is equal to do modulo two, which is equal to zero.
So zero here being printed.
Again, going up to f of five, it's f f of two is telling f a five, hey f of five, continue with
that program and print f the percentage de of and model two.
So F five is equal to an modulo two five model to 502 is two point five.
If we divide, five by two is two point five and the remainder is zero point five times two is equal
to one, so the remainder is equal to one.
Again, it will print one.
Here it's telling f five eight four five go up and continue f of 10 there the program execution.
So print f it will print here and Model two, which is an equal to five.
So an equal let density.
So 10 Model two is equal to zero because five divided by two is or 10 divided by two is five and there
is no remain there.
So the remainder is here is equal to zero.
So five.
Or 10 modulo two as equal to zero.
OK, now f of 10 is telling f of 20 hey f of 21, continue the executing the program.
I have finished this and go and print F and Model two and Model two in this case and Model two, and
this case is equal to twenty one model to twenty one over two is equal to ten point five.
We remove the decimal part zero point five times two equal to one.
So this is the remainder of this division.
So do any one.
Modulo two is equal to one.
And here we print f the function them the function of and modulo two and the result of.
And therefore, if we pass twenty one four to this question, it will give us one zero one zero one.
And this is the binary representation of the one.
No.
OK.
I hope you understand the recursion and in the simplest way, and this is the way you understand and
master recursion by practicing more and more questions.
So I hope you understand that and you solve this by your own.
And I am waiting your comments and any questions.